CV

Olof Landahl

E-mail

oloflandahl@hotmail.com

Homepage

www.oloflandahl.com

SUMMARY

Web/Software Developer with over 5 years experience

Solid JavaScript & C#/.NET experience, developing Web and Windows applications using jQuery, HTML5, CSS, ASP, WebForms, MVC, WinForms, etc.

Front end development implementing interactive UIs and visualisations, both professionally and in my spare time.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mar 2013 - current

Vodafone (as contractor from DiUS), Sydney

Working as front end web developer with vodafone.com.au and internal pages. This included not only front end, but also some back end work. I was using JavaScript, jQuery, jQuery plugins, HTML5 and CSS3 as well as Java, PHP and CMS (Fatwire & Movable Type).

Unit testing of front end code was mandatory and was implemented using Jasmine and Qunit.

I was developing for both desktop and mobile devices using responsive design.

The type of work was changing with new priorities and requirements coming in on a daily basis. I was part of a team transitioning to be fully agile. This included a lot of training and coaching from agile professionals.

Jun 2008 - Jan 2013

TIBCO Software, Spotfire Division, Gothenburg, Sweden

TIBCO Software is a company that offers infrastructure software and has over 4000 customers and 3000 employees worldwide. The Spotfire core development is in Gothenburg, Sweden, where around 60 people work.

TIBCO Spotfire is a visual data analysis tool used for ad-hoc analysis, decision making and reporting and has customers in life sciences, energy, financial services and many other industries.

I worked full time as a developer in the Visualisations team, with both the web client and windows client, using mainly JavaScript, jQuery, C#/.NET 4.0, ASP WebForms and WinForms. The main work duties were planning, designing, implementing, unit testing, bug fixing and engineering support.

I was mainly focusing on visualisations and graphical work but also worked with data access, user interfaces, user interactions, library-server integration, export and other parts of the product. My work has covered mostly front end but also back end.

A selection of highly successful projects where I've been one of the main contributors:

Re-implementing the tabular plots to be web based

A large refactoring of the tabular plots to make the rendering and interaction strictly JavaScript based. This had great advantages of having a shared implementation for the windows and web client, getting rid of a third party framework with a lot of bugs and allow for easier style configuration.

Implementing the main data panel UI

The web based data panel was crucial when the support for live external data sources was added. It's especially useful for getting a good overview of cube data which was a deal breaker with a large important client.

Adding 'top n rows' feature in the cross table plot

This was not a mandatory requirement but I thought it would be of high value to customers and rather easy to implement. The positive response from customers was huge, given the small size of the feature.

Developing a large and complex application together with very talented coworkers has given me strong skills in problem solving, code quality, design patterns, user interaction and group dynamics.

Feb 2008 - Jun 2008

Carmenta AB, Gothenburg, Sweden

Carmenta is a company with about 50 employees, based in Gothenburg, Sweden. With focus on geospatial technology the company offers both a map engine product as well as tailored GIS solutions. Main customers are in the security, enterprise and defence markets.

I worked mostly with GIS applications implemented in .NET/C#. I was also responsible for doing quality checks on geographical data.

EDUCATION

March 2012 (1 week)

Microsoft .NET Framework 4.0, Web Applications Development Informator, Gothenburg, Sweden

A Microsoft course that included MVC and Web Forms development, Entity Framework, authentication, Ajax and more.

September 2009 (1 week)

Core & Advanced Foundations of Microsoft .NET 2.0 Development Informator, Gothenburg, Sweden

A Microsoft course for developing applications with the .NET Framework, including serialization, deployment, localisation, encryption, services, threading and more.

2002 - 2008

Master of Science in Media Technology and Engineering Linköping University, Norrköping, Sweden

A computer science program with focus on visualisation, programming, image processing and computer graphics.

Some important courses were multi variable calculus, linear algebra, data structures and algorithms, computer technology, communication and user interfaces, information visualisation and modelling and animation. A complete list of courses and grades is supplied on request.

My thesis project was conducted at Carmenta where I created a weather visualisation application for the aerospace industry. The project was very well received at the company and they offered me a permanent position.

SKILLS

Languages Swedish: mother tongue

English: fluent, IELTS overall score 8.5 out of 9

French: limited

Programming & Frameworks

JavaScript/jQuery/Ajax/D3

Jasmine/QUnit HTML5/CSS3/SASS

Mobile/Responsive Design

ASP .NET (Web Forms & MVC3)/Java/PHP

XML/JSON

C#/.NET 2.0-4.0/NUnit

Windows Forms

CMS/Fatwire/MovableType

SQL C++

Software & Tools

Microsoft Visual Studio 2008-2012

JetBrains Resharper

Eclipse Sublime Tortoise SVN TIBCO Spotfire FxCop/StyleCop

Adobe Photoshop/Illustrator/Lightroom/InDesign

3D Studio Max

CERTIFICATES

October 2009 Microsoft .NET Framework, Application Development Foundation (70-536)

REFEREES

Referees supplied on request.